# **CJ WILLIAMS**

# UX/UI DESIGNER, MARKETER, FRONT-END DEVELOPER



**Phone** 

406.579.1985



**Email** 

cj@silencekillsdesign.com



**Portfolio** 

hirecj.com

## SOCIAL



LinkedIn

/cjwilliamsworks



GitHub

/silencekillsdesign



Codepen

/silencekillsdesign

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Treehouse Academy**

Front-End Development Techdegree teamtreehouse.com
2014 - 2022

### **Montana State University**

Graphic Design & Music Technology Bozeman, MT 2003 - 2008

## **SKILLS**

- UX / UI / IA DESIGN
- HTML / CSS / JS / VUE / NUXT
- ADOBE CC & FIGMA
- MANAGEMENT & LEADERSHIP
- SEMRUSH / HUBSPOT
- TECHNICAL SEO / SEM / PPC
- E-COMMERCE MANAGEMENT
- PROJECT MANAGEMENT

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- GOOGLE UX DESIGN
- GOOGLE DIGITAL MARKETING
- ADVANCED GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- CERTIFIED NUXT MASTER
- HUBSPOT INBOUND

## PROFILE

Hi! I'm CJ, a UX Designer, Front-End Web Developer, and E-Commerce Director, with 10 years of management experience. I am a strong and compassionate leader with a multi-disciplinary career background, able to work across teams fluidly. I make data-informed decisions with logic and understanding. My greatest strengths are will, wit, empathy, and awareness. I'm excited to join a team with shared goals, values, and ethics so we can make awesome things that make life better for all.

## EXPERIENCE

#### **Greenridge Farm**

Director of UX and E-Commerce / 2021 - Present

- · Led creative design on new brand identity, packaging, and digital spaces
- · Created and maintained design systems and prototypes in a Figma
- · Migration of domains and API connections to new Greenridge e-commerce site
- Implemented team workflows to optimize efficiency in product development
- Strategically improved organic and technical SEO, increasing web traffic over 180%
- Led product development strategy to increase year-over-year online sales by 400%

#### **Hoists.com** (and sister companies: Sievert Electric, Sievert Crane, and CES)

Director of Customer Experience and E-Commerce / 2021 - 2023

- Information Architecture for over 2500 product SKU configurations
- Directed all UX research, design, and ongoing development
- Management of web dev and UX across all additional business entities
- Technical SEO, SEM, SMM, and PPC strategy, management, and reporting
- Created infrastructure for Dev, UX, Customer & Sales Support staff
- · Managed growth of department, creating 4 new roles within the company
- Launched to a reach of over 50k unique visitors in our first year, with paid traffic netting 36k clicks, 1.8M impressions on a \$2k/mo. budget

#### SilenceKillsDesign

Agency Owner - UX Design, Front-End Development, Marketing / 2007 - 2020

- UX Research, Development, Architecture and Design for primarily B2B clientele
- Creation and Management of multiple clients' online presence and identity
- SaaS admin interface design for web apps for integration with Oracle
- Brand asset design for digital and print mediums
- Website and e-commerce architecture, development, design, and optimization
- Owned SEO / SEM / PPC / SMM strategies, tracking, and reporting
- Track and report on KPI and goal completion

### **Xtant Medical**

Manager of UX and Digital Marketing / 2012 - 2016

- UX Design and Ffront-end development of public-facing site
- Design and development of investor and internal sales portal
- · SEO, SEM, PPC, SMM, Ad Purchasing
- · Brand design, product design, management, and growth marketing